# kendall goodwin

Seattle, WA

W: http://kendallgoodw.in E: kendall.a.goodwin@gmail.com

P: (36o) 903-2725

GH: http://github.com/kendallgoodwin

## **ABOUT**

I'm a Seattle-based front end developer with a passion for bold design and streamlined user experience.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript

**Frameworks**: Node.js, Express, Angular, jQuery **Database Tools**: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL **Other**: Photoshop, Responsive Design, GitHub, AJAX,

JSON, Bootstrap, Heroku

#### **EDUCATION**

# **General Assembly**

Full Stack Web Development Certification, 2016

# **Seattle Pacific University**

B.A. Creative Writing & English Literature, 2010

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Best Ever**

A social app for music lovers to debate the best song ever. Users can create entries and upload an accompanying image, as well as view individual entries and user profiles. This app was created using the MEAN stack, Express-JWT, Cloudinary, Javascript, and Bootstrap.

#### **Homeventory**

A home inventory app that allows users to keep track of grocery and household items. Created as part of a group project at General Assembly using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, bcrypt, Facebook OAuth, jQuery, and Bootstrap, and utilizes the Factual API.

#### **Memory: Literary Alcoholics Edition**

A traditional memory game featuring history's most infamous literary lushes, built with HTML and vanilla Javascript and jQuery.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **General Assembly**

Full Stack Web Developer, March 2016-June 2016 Spent 12 weeks in an immersive full stack web development course, consisting of 480 hours of instruction, 60-70 hours of work per week, and 4 portfolio projects. Focus on building fluency in programming languages like HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and Ruby, as well as other frameworks and tools such as Node.js, Express, Rails, Angular, AJAX, JSON, and PostgreSQL.

# Tom Douglas Restaurants, The Pink Door, PF Chang's China Bistro

Lead Host, November 2012-March 2016 Coordinate the strategic seating of our very small restaurant during high volume hours. Interact with guests under high-stress circumstances and always maintain a gracious and customer service-oriented attitude toward all.

#### Alaska Airlines Magazine/Horizon Air Magazine

Editorial Intern, November 2012-February 2013 Fact-checked stories and wrote short (150-200 word) articles for both magazines about events taking place in cities within the airlines' flight paths, which included researching and proposing event topics and conducting interviews with sources.

# Northwest Administrators, Inc.

Document Review Specialist, June 2012-October 2012 Proofread, edited, and typed all outgoing correspondence for the Contract Review and Pension Accounting departments, logged and distributed all contract correspondence, processed interdepartmental requests for archived contracts.

# **Gerrits Family**

Au Pair, October 2011-March 2012
Provided childcare for a Dutch family's two
elementary-aged children, including daily meal
preparation, shuttling to and from school and afterschool activities, and helping build their English
language skills through verbal conversation and games.